in this five video series you're going
to witness Pakistan and Pakistani food
like you've never seen it before oh okay
so many things have not expected that
are happening right now here in this
country of 220 million you'll find an
incredible culinary range no matter
which street you go you'll find tons of
amazing street food from fiery street
food in Pakistan's mega cities 4 kg over
8 lb of meat we have to eat the whole
thing we you have to eat most of it I
have to eat most of it to rare Village
food in the northernmost mountains of
hunza Valley he's going to take off the
lid and we unveil the most magnificent
pot of yak and rice I have ever seen in
my life it all starts after dark in the
food lover city of
laor it has finally happened after years
of planning I'm in Pakistan baby I'm
here right now with my man javel we're
at a restaurant with about seven kawas
these huge cooking platforms that are
slightly recessed it's a perfect place
to kind of shallow fry food here they're
making chicken but not just any chicken
this is a super spicy chicken tonight
I'm going for their best seller the
fiery mouth melting tawa
chicken before hitting this oversized
flat top the chicken already been part
cooked next they add their own homemade
Masala containing white pepper black
pepper Ginger saffron and yogurt then
add Supreme quality cooking oil what
makes this dish special isn't the
supreme cooking oil or the Masala it's
this a hecko of atomic level green
chilies next add lemon and cook until
all the flavors blend together coming
one glistening fiery red
[Music]
Hue finally when it's ready to serve the
chicken is wrapped in a chipati and sent
out into the
world this dish started with this
restaurant AR re chhara and this
restaurant started over 40 years ago we
have the bread and we're digging
straight do you actually eat the chili
yes of course okay is that respectable
all right I'll give you that she'll give
me that all right
[Music]
oh
uhoh the thing about this is you can't
stop eating it even if you're burning
absolutely a flavor explosion and then
uh like the Aftershock you taste the
lightning and then you wait for the
Thunder yes oh that's pretty
good when you bite into the chicken
first you taste oh what is it like
little bit of a charring type of thing
it comes from the tawa that they cook on
in China what they would call walk hay
like tasting the walk it's like tasting
the tawa I want to really load this up
let's do it I got to go bigger I got to
go bigger load it up I want to earn your
respect I can get the respect of a local
we have more
chili is that
good are you sure oh my God we have a
winner oh my
[Music]
God thank you I want to say I'll regret
that later but I think pretty soon yeah
wait for down to five but it's so good
so good it's so addictive luckily on the
side we have a tiny bowl of yogurt to
cool us down uh you would hope joining
me on this epic protein pilgrimage I'm
not need to chug it down she's a
culinary student and a fashioned blogger
based in her hometown of lore I'm here
for about a week it's not a long time
but it's enough to get a snapshot of
food here at Pakistan now I know not a
lot of people know that Pakistan and
India used to be one country called
Hindustan I've been in India a lot I've
had a lot of food there but what would
you say differentiates food in Pakistan
from India I think Northern Indian food
is very similar the kind of food you get
in Punjab or Delhi amitz that's very
close to the Pakistani food but South
sou Indian food or Bengali food that's
completely different so the common
factors I think would be that they're
big on meat we're big on meat they're
big on oil we're big on o
yeah is that the prayer about how long
does that take 3
minutes this is a Muslim Nation what
percentage of people here would you say
is Muslim nearly all nearly all yes very
very small percentage of minorities
India of course is a big population so
the diversity is much more too not just
religion but you know the different
regions have a very disting culture so
it seems the other big difference would
be that everyone's eating Halal here
Halal yes so no pork although not much
pork in India anyways also in India they
don't eat so much beef okay so that's a
pretty notable difference right there
all right this is a good start we have a
lot more to
see our street food Journey has led us
here a one-of-a-kind all the cart menu
what time do restaurants close here 2
a.m. yes only here you're pointing to
the body parts you most crave oh that's
the fact if uncertain it's always good
to start with the sheep butt fat hold on
I recognize this I just came here from
usbekistan this is a fat tail sheep this
is that this is called the Dumba just
the tail oh so we call the whole animal
Dumba Dumba the Dumba is like the
foundation of USC cooking so many dishes
start with the fat that kind of melts
off of that and then they cook in the
fat is that what they're doing here
that's what they're going to do here yes
all right a typical order should contain
a variety of meat cuts for a more
Dynamic flavor and texture experience
this is 1 kg some fat some neck some
joint and this going to be delicious how
big do they go cuz some of those pots
are quite big they have an option of
going as big as 4 kilos also for that's
8.8 lb
y along with the meat the real locals
know that certain sheep organs must be
specially requested you know like the
secret menu at In-N-Out that's kidney
right that's kidney and that's
testicle do women eat testicles in
Pakistan I do so great what do you like
about the testicle it's just the flavor
and how they make it and also can I say
the mouth feel
yeah yeah I think you just did I did
with our meat ready we head to the fire
pits we're highly skilled smoke tolerant
chefs juggle over a dozen cast iron pots
at various points in their cooking
process these guys are seriously
impressive Chef how do you handle the
smoke he's used to it how long did it
take him to get used to it he's been
doing it for 18 years so holy cow
welcome to ilas Dumba Kahari we've
learned about the Dumba now this is the
Kahari so is it frying is it boiling I
would say it's uh between brazing and
stir frying and also stewing a little
bit 4 kgs over 8 lbs of meat we have to
eat the whole thing we you have to eat
most of it I have to eat most of it he
adds salt then green chilies for spice
ginger for aromatics and tomato for acid
I'm sorry that India is my only point of
comparison but there there's usually an
onslaught of ingredients like 15 spices
would not be enough in in India but here
it's essentially maybe four different
things contributing some flavor on
average about 700 lb of meat is cooked
and consumed here each day serving over
1,000 guests but it's not just about the
Kahari tonight the charcoal grill is
also full of action so I heard this is
really special you won't find this
anywhere this is also from the sheath
deliver WRA in fat oh I've heard of this
this is like call Fat it's like the fat
lining from the
animal exactly
right can we try a
piece we can have all of it he seemed
like he was yelling at you no no he was
happy okay he's very aggressive with his
enthusiasm oh these all look so dang
delicious wow I've heard that you should
only eat two at most or it'll give you
hot flashes even even if you're a man I
don't know how that
works
mhm wow but the flavor it's really
really hot it's so sheepy the liver is
nice it's super warm the fat on the
outside is Juicy and it gives you that
first hit of flavor when you take a bite
into it absolutely but also a little
gaming you a fan of the gaminess I do I
I do like it that's our appetizer we're
going to head in and eat the big the
four kilos
[Music]
next right here the king tons of
different cuts in here you kind of just
have to go piece by piece and figure out
what it
is oh wow it is so juicy I'm not
surprised cuz he cooked it so long but I
just couldn't tell is it going to be
tough is it going to be tender very
tender over here so this is called the
pavi Nan also known as a Kam Roti it's a
different way of making it than a nan
well what's the difference between the
and a non cuz it looks like a non and
not so much like a non-n years the
treatment of the D of the N are they
more hostile towards it they treat it
badly yes that's good it's interesting
cuz you said maybe there's not a ton of
differences between here and India but
I've never had anything like this in
India this is wildly different because
this is from the Northern parts of
Pakistan woo that's good I used to love
that as a kid I used to fight everyone
to get all the marrow should we try some
kidney okay let's do that M mhm livering
but not kind of like dry like liver
really nice and moist oh I'm looking for
testicle the testicle how do you
identify it it's
small that's one
way yep there's something about the
sauce and the cast iron has made it
really dense so it's not like fatty and
jiggly that's the part that bothers
people because the moisture is gone out
it's cooked at such heat I bet this is
one of those Foods you could give to
people and tell them halfway through by
the way you've eaten 17 testicles and
they' have no idea so good I'm very
impressed this is just our second
location we have a lot more to see still
let's finish this first I like it I
tried to get out of eating 8 lb of meat
but no
[Music]
love bro so thank you so much for making
it happen thank you so much for coming
you've been long awaited meet Ali a
Pakistani man on a mission to introduce
his country's Cuisine to the world we
were going to come here before Co and
then Co happened and that was not on my
calendar at all he's the reason in
Pakistan for this series but of all
places why start in laor lots of many
cultures from different part of Indo par
subcontinent merged
here so you'll find A Taste of India
you'll find a taste of Middle East LA
heart embraced all those spices all
those cultures and made it its own does
Pakistan need to distinguish itself from
India when it comes to food they are
very high on spices here you find spices
a bit more moderate and we love our meat
if you the meat lover Pakistan is your
place
[Music]
the street food Journey continues this
is after dark in Pakistan right now
we're in a new joint a new location I'm
with Ain and he is saucing up some of
these fish this is Ru it's a local type
of carp freshwater carp the ru fish is
marinated with a paste consisting of
garlic ginger Corum seed cumin chili and
salt it marinates for 2
hours from here it's going to head to
the fryer we're going to fry the heck
out of it and it's going to taste
delicious question mark I'm not sure I'm
going to find out pretty
soon sadik mle F Ro has been selling
this very same recipe for over 50 years
starting as a cart and evolving to one
of Lor's bus stop
destinations we've been a bent sheep
heavy and this is something refreshing
something light very
light we break the bread and we dig
right in and also I have to warn you
it's going to have a lot of these small
fish bones uhoh that looks nice you have
another bone in there by the way I can
see oh thank you save my life give it a
little bit of a dip yeah this is a
Tamarind
sauce oh wow that's a lot of flavor it's
interesting cuz we're talking about
Pakistani food versus Indian food here
it seems like they're more likely to
focus on just a few ingredients and
really concentrate on just those flavors
so I taste a garlic I taste cumin like I
taste each individual spice one of the
very good chefs that I met in my life
said that a good dish only needs five
ingredients oh yeah that's it any more
than that and you're making it too
complicated sorry subcontinent of India
we're also on the subcontinent of India
oh yeah if you get a bone in your throat
what do you do get somebody do it really
depends on the size of the bones you can
also throw up sometimes these are great
tips
yeah overall it's quite delicious carb
has a bad reputation for being muddy and
uh earthy because it's a bottom feeder
but here it's quite delicious I don't
taste any of that it's an aggressive
fish with an attitude and so you have to
treat it just as aggressively and that's
what they've done here it's magical cuz
it's hot it's steaming it's crunchy and
the flavors just come out so powerfully
we have one location left it's just on
the road we should head there now we
finish this before after we finish this
entire thing for sure we will do it off
camera what you know about Pakistani
chicken I know what you're thinking you
already saw it in the beginning of the
video no this is completely different
right here we've come to another
restaurant and man rotisserie chicken
but not done with a machine no this is
done with the touch of a human this man
right here
oh we're holding hands up in this street
side rotisserie they marinate whole
chickens for 24 hours smoking them in a
vinegar and spice blend containing green
chilies garlic ginger and whole spices
when it's time they're stabbed and
skewered over hot charcoal for about an
hour each skewer has one chicken on it
look I'm like a samurai but with
delicious food on my sword and this oh I
just scared it it peed a little bit
after roasting it's scored and deled
with lime and Masala this chicken pairs
best with basati rice cooked with
carrots mint dried dates and saffron
you'll only find this creation at
Khalifa pooi Saji serving over 1,000
customers every day for the last 18
years gosh you know it's our last
location here we've had some chicken and
we have some skewers too these are beef
skewers this is beef Kebab Kebab I
should say there are two types of Kebabs
you'll find in this region the shish
kebab refers to seasoned cute cubed meat
that's skewered and grilled then the
seed Kebab that's minced meat carefully
shaped on a skewer by hand and blasted
with hot charcoal heat until they're
dripping with flavor with the seat
kebabs here beef is
King ground up along with oil onion
ginger garlic green chilies and
condensed milk I'm going to just eat it
plain to begin
with that really nice so delicious
there's so much flavor spicy but there's
so much seasoning that it becomes a
texture within the SE like I'm chewing
on ground spices I'm going to try giving
it a little bit of a dip this is
coriander yes and mint with yogurt oh
yeah you're dirty yep and that's going
to balance off a little bit of the
overpowering of the spice this is like
heartburn and this is like Pepsi AC Yes
somewhere in the middle it's TS down the
spice of bit so it's not so intense it's
called a seat Kebab did the seat people
invent this oh no all right that was a
dumb question so it's not sik Kebab it's
kebab and is a skewer
I feel bad for my audience watching
right now it's one of the best flavors
and it's something you can only get you
know in this type of an environment I
mean you can probably go into a
restaurant with air conditioning too and
a little bit of soundproofing you have
to come to a place like this to lore to
the street side it's made fresh they are
not playing as safe with the spices it's
really spicy exactly that brings me this
right here the
chicken on a huge bed of Biryani is that
bani that's not Biryani bani is very
spicy Diner taste Middle Eastern oh okay
we have our chicken right here they
ripped open the chest just spread a
bunch of seasoning in
[Music]
there oh there's plenty of Masala on
there it tastes like pure salt and red
chili powder and cumin wow that's a lot
of spices you need to have it with the
rice that's how we eat it's got a really
good balance sure I think it's the same
as like that long grain bani rice yeah
the basmati rice is the same I love the
texture of that I love how it feels it's
almost like eating little short noodles
sometimes so
yummy it has been a pleasure sharing all
this food with you and getting really my
Taste of Pakistan with you I'm so glad
thank you so much thank you so
much today I'm on a mission to hunt down
the body parts the feet are full of tiny
Bones the off Cuts oh my gosh the oals
this is like game on game all cooked up
in unique ways to create some startling
mouth magic it's like when your light
flashes before your eyes except for it
was this goat's life was flashing
through my mouth it all starts with a
hearty
breakfast good morning from Pakistan it
is day two we're back at it and we're
starting with a pretty tricky breakfast
pretty much before the sun comes up
people are coming here for this this pot
is filled with goat heads split into
three parts the brain the cheeks and the
tongue I've never seen it displayed this
way but it makes sense it's early
morning you can't handle a whole head so
you can choose which head part you want
this hey meat has been stewing in red
chilies cumin lemon and Liquid Smoke
since 4:00 a.m. this morning can I see
that all right cut number one this is
where here cheeks cheeks Meet The Man
Behind the meat Mr hany he's been
cooking goat heads here at ala Hot
Corner Temple since 1963 all right go
cheeks right here I don't know if it's
both cheeks or One Cheek I do see a
dimple though that's
nice it's the tongue of oh my gosh okay
so here is the tongue but honestly it's
more than the tongue every muscle that
comes along with it is in there too it's
going to be juicy and juicy M this is
one more part here oh take a look it's
brain for breakfast but he's going to
open it up for us so he takes a knife he
finds the exact right pain points oh yes
just like taking out some bone marrow
he's pounded out the brain it looks like
if you ride a motorbike with no helmet
in Pakistan nobody wears a helmet on
their bike it's going to be like that
guys wear your helmet or um that's you
this is brain for breakfast it is one of
the most unique breakfast I've seen
anywhere I love that when people wake up
here they just go metal this is Hardcore
early morning food it's heavy it's
interesting unique body parts and I
can't
wait have you ever had brain this early
in the morning of course I'm from lore
to explore lore's most unique meat
offerings I've enlisted the help of a
local Chef Robia so is this a common
thing even for ladies it doesn't matter
if you're a man or a woman Loris Love
Heavy breakfast let's jump into it so we
have some bread we have three different
cuts of head on the side here buttermilk
what is buttermilk buttermilk is a
fermented dairy drink here they make mix
it with sugar and beat it until it
becomes thick and
[Applause]
delicious oh the cream is literally rise
to the top here that is so good and so
heavy well we're just getting started oh
that's
delicious starting with cheek I'm trying
to figure out what these bunny ears were
that's the mouth so I'm literally
holding it by the lips right now it is
saying don't eat me get some of my juice
in your
mouth so try it out M oh that's very
nice it's very pleasing it has a nice
mouth that's something people say who
review food nice what
feel coming up next we have tongue this
is what I mean like it's not just the
tongue it's also all this connective
tissue behind the tongue that stuff is
delicious and it's different than the
tongue itself
seriously that's interesting good flavor
but you do have to proceed with caution
cuz there are a lot of bones in there
and I thought it was just shattered
fragment maybe from the guy who act this
down but no it just happens to have a
lot of little bones in the back of the
tongue area this is the tongue itself
the tongue has no bones I'm going to
peel it open and reveal that soft goat
Pate inside try it out not ging at all
clean but bold like a heavy taste oh
that's
yummy let's move on to the brain this is
the skull that's holding the brain I
think I can just remove it by hand I'm
going to tap it and see it just leak out
onto the bread like it's giving birth
that is a lot of brain cheers
M it's so creamy first it tastes like
brain but then it gets really Livery
very heavy but it has some nice flavor
to it I think maybe I just put on smidge
too much I'm going to have one more and
I'm going to reduce the brain matter
give that a
dip mhm genuinely enjoyable I love
it how long have you lived in laor well
I'm originally from here but I grew up
in the Philippines but I've always had a
connection to lore we've been coming
here every year my entire life and I've
returned back from the last 2 and 1/2
years when you came back to live here
fulltime what do you notice that people
from here don't notice about the city so
I came in as a chef so over here what I
find is the food is very meat focused
but highly balanced as well and people
genuinely care a lot about their
relationships with each other and their
relationships with food so that is
something that I think goes unnoticed
over here because people are so just
used to being themselves but someone
coming from the outside will notice that
Hospitality really
[Music]
well if that breakfast didn't do it for
you next up an underappreciated oal
offering prepared by chefs who are good
with their hands and good with their
feet
too Al I'm still in Pakistan today I'm
focused on some of the more exotic
unique Foods featured in the city of
lore as I travel around the world I
really enjoy looking for the foods that
some might consider exotic because it
always has a story that comes with it
but we're also in a country where people
eat just Halo food so most of the food
is going to be not so many lizards and
reptiles and bugs can you think of
anything here that is a bit out of the
ordinary especially for a Westerner this
is Aldi I call him The Unofficial
ambassador of Pakistani food and he's
the whole reason I'm here when it comes
to food we pakistanis are very efficient
every organ is used to prepare the food
so that you can call exotic one
interesting thing about is that
whichever organ you eat your own organ
is going to get strengthened so for
example if you eat G Beed probably going
to run marathons what about the
testicles uh again a
marathon is there anything in laor that
was too strange or unique for you I
haven't go stomach yet and you will try
it so you are about to know more about
laor than me
even here they have a very unique col of
mean you don't find it everywhere you go
but they specialize in this somewhat
strange offcut here could you pick these
up for me yes get a load of that these
are two goat stomachs they are huge I'm
going to give it a little bit of a
snip offensive this is one of the
hardest ingredients to cook with cuz it
is so incredibly gy some people don't
like goat meat it's because they
consider that gamy but this is like game
on game but soon hopefully they're going
to work their magic here it looks like
they know what they're doing the dishes
they're preparing already they look
delicious so let's see what they can do
with
this after the stomach is cleaned it
must be cut down to sides and if your
hands are full you could always use your
feet is goat stomach a common ingredient
found in restaurants here in
La this is Zan Amed head chef here at
Arif restaurant not so much but
definitely it's one of those dishes that
people make at home really well the cut
down portion stomach is moved to a giant
cauldron of garam masala a spicy broth
made from cinnamon cumin fenugreek
garlic onions and tons of oil what is
good about the
stomach it's really good for your liver
and it has really great health
properties that's why people enjoy it a
lot which is good cuz I drink way too
much what help for then nice after 6
hours of stewing it's ready for the next
step where it sizzles on a skillet with
ginger black pepper and coriander the
tough part about the goat stomach is the
Taste is very powerful so do you try to
cook that taste out of it or do you
Embrace that taste ory basically to
erase that flavor that is not that
enjoyable these guys wash it upwards of
15 to 18 times that's really what it is
whenever you have any kind of off cut
it's about treating that really well and
with respect so I see that happening
over here all right I'm excited I can't
wait to try this
out flipping goat stomach yeah we're
really going hard today and how is it
like for you seeing somebody cut with
their foot I think it's good to have
three appendages at work otherwise you
can only cut with two hands I hope in
the bathroom it says employees must wash
hands and feet don't count on
it we have it here it looks good thank
you is it just none it's not none so
it's a non
none I'm going to start with just
stomach try it out
[Music]
I like that way more than I thought I
would I like it too oh it's spicy [__] I
like the spice yeah the goess is still
there but the way they seasoned it it's
like they're working with that flavor
and it's not overpowering but it does
blend with the other flavors in there
and a lot of the flavors that they put
in they're very conscious about which
flavor comes when into your mouth so you
have the warm spices first filling up
then you get the meat flavor then you're
left with the spice so each bite is a
whole experience and that comes through
a lot of like education that these guys
have doing the work that they do I can
see they really take pride in the food
all the steps they went through here I'm
really
impressed this is laor this city goes
back centuries and evidence of its
history can be seen and felt
everywhere this is the capital of the
Punjab Province it's also the second
largest city in this country the clatter
and clamor the pure raw energy takes me
back to cities like daaka or
Omar the difference is in the details
henna dyed hair Muslim skull caps known
as Takia the call to prayer five times a
day echoing out from the city's
tremendous
mosques just at the point of overwhelm
you can always sink your your complete
focus into the next street food stall
you cross paths with like this
place you know we had the head and I
felt like we were missing some balance
earlier now we've got the
feet there is perhaps no food more
commonly eaten in Pakistan then goat
meat from its head to its stomach all
the way down to its feet and you'll be
amazed what can be done with such a
humble ingredient that's a hook that's
why these creatures have such good grip
this is goat paa paa means Le in erdu
once the goat Trotters are hacked off
and thoroughly cleaned hundreds of them
are piled high in giant cauldrons and
braised for hours in a rich spicy
[Music]
broth the feet are full of tiny bones I
mean look at this what is going on here
is there any meat in here that's my main
question not really you really just
focus on the broth more than the bones
and the meat itself you want to grab a
little
Trotter uh-oh
[Music]
you were really ambitious with that oh
my gosh this is so rich it's flavorful
but I cannot believe someone would come
here and just get this it is just pure
fatty collagen with a delicious broth
pup I couldn't fill up on just pure
fatty collagen that is wild all right a
little bit more let me just combine it
with the bread yeah yeah almost every
restaurant in lore makes their own bread
fresh on the
spot one of my favorite things about
Pakistan so far is that almost almost
every restaurant we've gone to has had
their own bread making station so you're
getting it Super Fresh here Mr Muhammad
Tahir is in charge of the Tandoor right
now he's making a really unique type of
nun that I've only seen here in Pakistan
he's rolled out some of the dough and
then he uses this press he presses it
really hard and it's going to create
this beautiful texture on the final
product but then next this is the most
magical part right here he hits a dough
with some sesame seeds puts it on the
pillow and then puts it in the
tandor one thing you should pay
attention to anytime you see a hurman
look at his arm it will be completely
hairless I learned this when I was in
India cuz I tried putting in the bread
myself that burnt off all my arm hair
his right arm has no hair his left has
hair it's a mismatch for ladies maybe
it's like an alternative form of hair
removal try it out so some of the first
ones he put in are already freaking done
my man can you treat my hands as the
basket yes I got it I can handle
it
woo not too hot for me break off peace I
mean this is why they call it breaking
bread
cheers oh yeah that's a good stuff
piping hot very toasty and delicious on
the inside thank you all right I got
some inside the bread nice dipping
action much so much cumin and cardamom
like overload lot a lot of spice I've
never had a broth like this it's so
strange it's almost milky you would say
you know because of everything inside it
you're like I can't scrape the oil away
to get into the curry it's all almost if
I into one yeah that's awesome I love it
I love the flavors but man that is so
rich and
heavy what kind of food are you serving
here cuz I looked at the menu on the
wall and it looks like it's wide ranging
you have a tower Zinger Burger you have
the Zinger wrap also you have goat
testicles are those in the same category
B welcoming us to his street food
Kingdom Mr SED azim sha so he wants to
cater to all kinds of people before the
street food was this stuff and now the
mood is changing into stuff so he wants
one place that sells
everything this place has it all from
Modern Comfort foods to more adventurous
options including something they call T
how do you say it t oh t
t Kat or takat is an iconic dish seen
and more often heard throughout Pakistan
if you took eighth grade poetry class
you'll know that takat talk is an anamia
for this sound
two karahi spatulas dancing over the
tawa slicing and dicing any organs that
enter its path while enticing passerbys
with a familiar sound it's one of those
things that is like a street favorite
around lore but as you can see
throughout the street everybody's
cooking on the front so it's a really
good Showcase of like here's what I can
do and that's why it's so popular all
right well we're about to indulge on a
lot of different organs here can you
give me a little organ tour so we have
the go testicles over here the brain the
heart as well and lamb ribs as well do
people pick one or do they mix them all
together have you and what do you
usually go with I go with the mutton
Chom I kind of keep it a little kosher
but today I'll be a little bit
adventurous sorry did you say
kosher I don't think many people are
keeping a kosher
here our Taco Talk starts with goat
brain ribs heart and testicles slid onto
the hot griddle add water and let it
cook a
bit using his trusty putty knives he
eviscerates these mutton Meats making
them
[Music]
unrecognizable add Ginger salt and more
water then
Steam on the side he prepares a tomato
paste green chilies caraway seed black
pepper and
more combine the paste with the meats
and add
[Music]
yogurt finally add about 13 cubes of
butter for good
luck more Ginger coriander green chilies
and
cream check it out our last meal he
docka Docker the heck out of this he put
a lot of butter in there and now you can
see there is a reservoir right here of
just butter let's dig into this the bone
still have some meat on them very little
yeah you can pull it out and you can go
for it oh I am wrong the bone has some
bone attached I will put that to the
side what do I do this is like a
tortilla these are butly Roes they're
really thin and they're very very large
you get a big piece and then you go in
this is such a mixture of everything and
I'm going to just do The Buttery really
yeah why not yeah you only live once and
you only die once too
cheers
oh wow there's a lot going on mhm I mean
my brain is trying to organize what is
what in there cuz I'm getting little
glimpses of everything I'm so glad that
it's not like iiz into one minced meat
thing you can actually get a lot it's
like when your life flashes before your
eyes except for it was this goat's life
was flashing through my mouth and I was
like o is that a testicle is there was a
heart and then the brain comes through
the most cuz it offers this really
congealed sticky fat creaminess that
binds it all together and it tastes a
bit Livery too now this is something
that you're not going to find everywhere
in the city cuz it is a real street food
if you go to a more modern restaurant do
they do a version of this yes they do do
versions of it but you will not get this
variety of meat over there because not
everyone is open to it and I think if
you come to a place like this to have it
then you will crave it more taka duck
generally is a very easy way to get into
all of these exotic meats yeah
absolutely it is a feast for your mouth
but also for your ears and for your eyes
you get to see all these Foods come
together but then you get a little music
action
too this has been an awesome day I want
to say thank you so much for joining me
I really enjoyed it I'm really glad that
we're giving the attention to places
like these and to meets like this
because sadly this is a dying are and we
need more people that are interested in
the food and you're not even from here
and you've enjoyed the food so that
speaks volumes about the potential of
this kind of dishes trying out foods
like this for me the most fun part is
having my expectations challenge feeling
one way about goost stomach thinking
there's no way this can work and then
seeing it just be incredible and that's
what today was the whole day so I loved
it a lot of new experiences I feel like
each day I'm learning more and more
about Pakistan and Pakistani
Cuisines Aldi and I are heading to the
Countryside to experience a different
way of life am I still in Pakistan and a
different approach to food oh okay so
many things I've not expected that are
happening right now it all starts with
breakfast we have Nasim BB who's a local
woman here with us and she's making a
very refreshing local drink for us which
is called lassy Lassie a dairy drink
made from fermented yogurt was actually
created in this part of the world so
then she puts in her wood blender she
secures this to it this kind of a twine
okay this is like a old school gym
equipment what makes this Lassie special
is that this yogurt came from Buffalo
milk it just going to take her 15 to 20
minutes of doing this exercise and then
the end product will be ready for
us separate the butter from the Lassie
and
enjoy am I still in Pakistan you very
much are in Pakistan considering the
kind of food that is in front of you
meet Ollie he's the one who made this
Pakistan food Journey possible by his
side the Lord of this mansion and the
host of today's event Mr M tar we have a
beautiful spread in front of us can you
kind of give me a food tour starting
from here these are the sweetened long
aged carrots that's a carrot yeah but
the sweetened
carrots wow that is super unique tastes
good like a carrot that's been soaking
in sugar for 3 days I've never had
anything like that from sweet pickles to
The Real Pickle mango pickles I didn't
know you could picklee a mango in this
part of the world mango is the most
famous form of the pickles oh very sour
super salty like a green olive times a
million but I like it
here these are patas but these are not
your ordinary patas because they have
different stuffings going on Pata is a
flatbread made from layers of dough with
delicious stuffings inside like spiced
potatoes it starts with the dough flour
salt oil and water fill that with mashed
potatoes coriander green chili
pomegranate seeds salt and red chili
powder add butter then a doughy lid on
[Music]
top it reminds me a little bit of T cha
with some stuffing in between it's super
heavy I can taste the potato inside I
love the bre part on the outside and
then it's just a burst of flavor from
the Masala super delicious I love
it next up the fenu Greek Pata smashed
with the mortar until it becomes a mushy
paste I'm going to try a little bit of
this one too M it's Super Fresh it
tastes more grassy like it has a really
strong flil taste to it that's really
good does the butter go on anything here
I use it on everything on everything
that's the result of the Lassie making
right exactly so this is the byproduct
or for me this is the product because I
love
butter mhm as a butter it's so different
I think it's unsalted right so this
you're just tasting really the pure fat
but without all the saltiness oh I love
it to cap off this breakfast we have the
homemade last SE oh it's so good it
tastes exactly like a sweet yogurt that
you can drink super delicious cold
refreshing I love
it this is a great way to start the day
a lot of new flavors and a lot of things
we haven't tried so far in previous two
days I've seen just a lot of meat here's
a little bit of variety in the breakfast
it's more about daily products but as
the day goes along things will start to
get meteor so we'll take you around
we'll give you the taste of some
authentic local goat grilled underground
and then obviously we'll give you a
taste of how the local people live all
right from here we got a lot to see with
breakfast out of the way prep for the
underground goat cooking can
begin cooking an entire goat will
require a little effort from a lot of
people all hands are on Deck let's move
some our task with the slaughter
dispatching the goat skinning it and
allowing it to hang so all its blood
will drain
out others prepare the fillings that
will soon go inside the goat par cooked
rice mixed with coriander seeds cinnamon
black pepper and dried plums now we need
the marination Squad blending together
yogurt lemon juice chili powder turmeric
powder fresh garlic and fresh ginger
last if we're going to roast an entire
goat whole we're going to need a little
heat cue the fire starter here we have
the pit where the goat is going to cook
pretty soon I'm still not sure what it's
going to look like when the goat goes in
here because there's a lot of dirt in
here too so are they going to wrap it
put it directly on the coals I'm not
sure but I'm going to find out pretty
soon with the prep complete there's only
one man who can bring all these elements
together meet chef Muhammad s pretty
soon it's going to be filled with this
marinade right here and if you create
more surface area like this more flavor
is going to get in there so he's cutting
all these little slits scoring it all
over the body right now he's cutting off
the butthole yeah we don't need that no
wants to eat that
anyways oh okay so now they're putting a
stick through that is why he was making
the bum a little bigger the stick goes
through it goes out the other end like
when you eat spicy Pakistani food from
here it's time to put the Masala inside
this is a ton of flavor in here but then
now he's putting in the rice the rice
has just been part cooked cuz it's going
to finish cooking while it's inside the
goat after the goat is fully stuffed
with Masala and rice the chef adds a
final Fistful of almonds raisins and
walnuts now he coats the animals from
head
to from neck to toe using the remaining
misala once the stomach is sealed it's
ready for the
[Music]
pit so we have our goat right here
Gentlemen please proceed anytime you're
burying an animal to cook there's always
a chance something could go wrong
they've kind of built a Groove into the
mud here so as they put it down the
stick fits perfectly into that Groove
timing right now I can see there's a
bunch of Embers underneath temperature
it's very hot the distance between the
Heat and the meat these grooves are not
deep enough so they're going to dig
these even deeper so the goat can go
deeper into the hole it all must come
together perfectly now they're going to
put it in the new more deeply dug
grooves if you're off it's over and
there are no redus they're bringing over
a giant lid it might look like a table
but it's absolutely not a table it's a
it's a lid I'm trying to figure out how
this works because there is still plenty
of space between the hole and the
lid oh bricks So This Is How They seal
it cuz we want to keep as much heat in
there as possible it's essentially
roasting and steaming at the same time
from here it's just about getting this
kind of sealed so all the heat is going
to stay inside as the goat is sealed so
is the fate of this meal what you'll
soon witness is one of the biggest food
fails in video broadcast history trust
me what I saw you don't want to see with
that said I'm still hoping for the best
I'm looking forward to
[Music]
it while the goat is roasting we're
heading out of the compound and deep
into the
[Music]
village where you'll witness an unusual
food creation you'd never see in the
[Music]
city we've gotone even further into the
countryside here they're making a
specialty what is this so this is sugar
can juice which is being condensed into
a hard form called
g g a local treat made from reduced
sugar cane juice this is how how sugar
was originally made in this region looks
incredible I love the color I mean it
looks like they put a bunch of turmeric
in there it's like vibrant yellow it
looks fake almost it's the residuals you
know coming up from the sugar cane juice
it will even become more yellowish and
brownish towards the end as it almost
like caramelizes
[Music]
exactly boiling down sugar cane juice
until the water evaporates and
crystallized sugar remains from this
point till the last product is going to
take 15 to 20 more minutes the cook adds
in ghee or clarified butter that is to
make it soft if they don't put ghee in
it the end product will be a bit too
hard once the sweet liquid becomes
viscous it's ready fill a wooden mold
with textured treats like almonds
pistachios raisins and melon seeds then
the thick sugar cane
goop they've poured it all from this
huge pan into here I'm putting my hand
just above it it is still really hot
this guy's like you better not put your
freaking hand print in there I'm not
going to but I might put my initials as
it cools down it's going to become
thicker and thicker eventually we're
going to be able to eat it but it's
still
hot we are near the final process right
here they kind of scrape it off they
don't exactly have like a scale or an
official measurement they just kind of
see what feels right in the moment
should we try it out yeah for sure let's
go for
it
w oh how would you describe them reminds
me of Korean corn tea but also you could
call it Pakistani fudge the nuts and
fruit in there give it some lovely
texture it's so sweet so addictive cuz
it is just that reduced down sugar what
we call sugar right now is something
very recent before that people actually
use these chunks of good to sweeten
their desserts or the milk and the teas
people say that this is healthier form
of sugar I'm not saying it's good for
your health like you should consume more
but if you have to have sugar might as
well have this than the sugar sugar this
has so much more character like salt and
soy sauce aren't the same same
comparison here white sugar and this not
the same to love
it back at our Farmhouse preparations
for tonight's Feast are in full
swing 3 hours have passed and it's
finally time to reveal the results of
our underground goat roast gentlemen
it's a big moment all day we've been
building up to this point right here in
this ground beneath this table there's a
goat it's either cooked or it's not
cooked This Is The Moment of Truth our
beloved Chef has few concerns that once
we un stable this goat whether it's
going to be cooked or not oh boy if it's
not on all the way pop it in the
microwave but we in the village we don't
have a microwave we put it back we put
it back all right let's
see who here's a moment right now so
they need to carefully remove
it oh I've never seen it go that looks
like that is this cooked cuz sometimes
it can look Smoky and not cooked but
could be cooked what's the chef say your
te he seems satisfied but his voice is
not very reassuring yeah he's that
radiating confidence
exactly H what does it feel like feels
medium maybe medium rare since I forgot
my meat thermometer at home we'll have
to take the goat to the table cut into
it and see for
ourselves we have a couple different
foods here the first one is this what is
this for our appetizer Bindy GH chunks
of goat slow cooked with onion garlic
ginger cumin and cashmir red chili
powder oh and don't forget the okra the
most vegetables I've seen since I got to
this country tons of okra let's try it
out classic okra little slimy super
solid
spicy oh my God incredibly spicy
wow I feel like a cat scratched my
throat you actually have that after
taste when you try okra okra okra I'm
talking about the chilies I'm talking
about
okra I do like the spiciness but it is
intense I tried some of the goat very
nice succulent juicy and so juicy
there's one more food here I want to try
that's a chicken
right this is chicken karaki dispatching
of the animal begins normal enough but
then something I've never seen before
rather than heating water and Feathering
the bird both feathers and skin are
quickly removed together a bit more
wasteful but certainly a more efficient
method the secret about skin is whenever
we are making curries we take the skin
off but when we cing the chicken that is
when we leave the skin the Des skin
chicken is cooked with tomatoes garlic
onions Ginger ghee and a local Masala I
can feel such a difference coming here
from the city where we're eating street
food which is meant to be super rich and
decadent here it has a much more of a
homecooked feel the flavors are a little
bit more gentle yes it's on the milder
side and this chicken is just not just
your ordinary chicken this is their home
raised organic DIY chicken all right I'm
going to try this
out oh yeah that's that organic
chewiness that's quite delicious very
[Music]
nice gentlemen the whole Community has
gathered here behind us right now this
is the future of Pakistan watching us as
we reveal the status of this goat the
goat doesn't have to be well done it
could just be medium or medium rare or
completely uncooked so we don't know cuz
there is a thick cake of Masala on the
outside so I feel like something here
has to be cooked and we're going to take
a bite I'm going to cut it open now and
see here we go
[Music]
guys is that the sharp sign okay here we
go cutting it
open that looks like half an inch
roughly is probably cooked and then
under that pretty raw I believe what I
see on the table is goat's
Revenge right when it was being
slaughtered I could see in her eyes you
can Slaughter me but you cannot eat me I
think if we skim the top a bit some
parts are done you want to try piece
cheers
cheers you forgot to put it in your
mouth I'm waiting for something to
happen to you it's going to take a
couple days I do like that Masala I
think it's meant to be you know cooked
to be honest the outer layer is fine
yeah let's not go deep I'm not Trevor
James I am not going deep today we're
going shallow how about I check the
contents of the
[Music]
stomach all right it's looking pretty
raw too I'm going to just put that back
I'm sure the Rope is
cooked you want some I'll save for later
maybe to hang
myself listen this happens sometimes we
went for something epic something
amazing something I think the chef has
not tried himself before right this is
from a different region this type ofing
so it's like me you know I'm like banana
bread I can make that nope can't do it
same thing here so he had the idea the
principles were in place just slipped a
little bit on the execution my guess is
that there was not enough coals the
coals probably cooled down too much when
we put it in there and I think when they
bricked it up even they kicked some dirt
down and that covered up even more coals
so firy went out an hour after I went in
there could be thousand Reasons
yeah aside from remote sugary sweets and
dirt holes containing uncooked goats
there's one last Countryside experience
one must endure before leaving this
place and if you thought thought that
goat was raw well it doesn't get more
raw than
[Music]
this bro what am I looking at here what
you're seeing here is a local WWE this
sport is called kabadi it's intense dude
and it's one of the main sources of
entertainment in these remote parts it's
very intense in two teams oppose each
other on the field of play The Objective
touch a a member of the opposing team
then run back to your side before any of
the four can smash you into the ground
what if I play against you we can do
that I'll do it let's do it let's do
[Music]
it even with the aggression hard hits
potential injuries scrapes bruises and
hairline
fractures out here on this barren field
littered with stones amongst those who
don't speak the same language you'll
find what words can't
[Music]
convey sportsmanship and
fraternity a place where the guy who
blindsides you sending you hurly toward
the rocky Earth is the same one who will
extend a hand to help pick you back
up out here you'll find the Pakistan
that escapes news headlines and
documentaries out here you'll find the
real Pakistan
[Music]
Pakistan has a population of 220
million you'll find similar culture
dress food and people in most cities
across the
country that is until you get
here in the far north of Pakistan Beyond
a multitude of mountain ranges you'll
find the hunza valley right now we're in
one of the many hunza villages on the
mountain side Mountain life here is so
completely different from any other
place in Pakistan and I love it because
Mountain cultures tend to maintain their
culture better over time a place so
isolated it's Customs around food
clothing and day-to-day life still
remain largely unaffected by the outside
world right now I'm on my way to a local
home to check out their kitchen and see
what's for
breakfast so we are continuing along
right now going through this Narrow Path
and up to a local home you have to come
up these steps here the steps are made
out of stone built into the house and
you have to be careful cuz there is no
railing here there are two ways to enter
on the bottom floor and here on the top
floor right through this miniature short
door met for Joe peshi you walk in you
see the main Gathering Room and then
after that the kitchen let's
go we're in the house of Sadia
Generations from her family have lived
here going 400 years back right now
Sadia and her mother are making
breakfast good morning how you
doing yeah how are you I'm also
just yeah she's making a couple
different items for breakfast right now
this is going to be a pancake and then
here is a fire she's flip the pan upside
down here so this would become the hot
surface for the pancakes to cook on what
is your favorite thing to cook is it
gatan new down
India no it's not that really I just
thought maybe cuz this entire room is
completely wallpaper papered with food
packages of Indian rice you know how
when you cook sometimes you throw away
the box and you have to dig it back out
cuz you're like wait how am I supposed
to cook this again they never have that
problem here gelin is a type of local
pancake made from wheat flour eggs water
and apricot oil right now she's taken a
piece of dough and she's used the dough
to spread butter on the pan here she's
got a big scoop oh yes this pan is
roaring hot even my knee is about to
catch on fire at this point H people
like hot because in hun very cold
at altitudes of at least 8,000 ft the
air is thin and the climate can be harsh
about time to give it a flip oh nice I
love the texture the pattern on here it
looks like the top down view of this
Village when you look at
this houses built into the mountain side
hug up against each other so no space is
wasted the thick Stone outer walls
stabilize temperatures inside when it's
hot or when it's cold where is the smoke
going there oh there's a hole there
hunza homes the kitchen is located in
the heart of the house radiating heat
and dispensing food in this house each
floor has a kitchen we're on the second
floor right now there's a skylight above
us so that's letting in all this natural
light and then there's this glass box
right here which lets in even more light
for the floor below what is this room
normally used for it's for summer time
you sit in here and so you eat here yeah
do you sleep here yeah how many people
sleep in this room 10 be honest out of
10 people how many
snore uh three
three we have a lot of different food
here some dishes I haven't seen anything
like this this trip so far we have the
pancakes I saw you make that and then
what is this one dry apricot soup
rehydrate the dried apricots in hot
water add crumbs of dough and weed flour
and cook until the mixture becomes thick
it looks so much more complex maybe
because there's just so many different
colors of apricot like dark ones and
light ones and it's created this
beautiful like orangey brown heel to the
broth which is also quite thick try out
M it's very sweet obviously apricot
flavor it feels more like a dessert than
anything else this is addictive 90% of
the food that you will have here one
common ingredient is going to be apricot
so again the soup has dried apricots
this soup has apricot
seeds this is a type of noodle soup dish
smash the apricot kernels or seeds then
add them to a pot of hot water to create
a broth season with a little bit of salt
I saw these earlier I thought they were
almonds so they look like almonds but
basically apricot seeds these are so
good they're like a much better almond
they're not like all dry and chalky
they're half the size I love these the
noodles are made fresh from scratch weed
flour salt eggs and water mixed together
to make the dough knead it then cut into
small short strands and
[Music]
cook M it is such gentle flavors tastes
homemade you can taste like the wheat
from the wheat noodle this soup is like
my kind of soup I like my soup to be a
bit lighter joining our meal Ali a
Pakistani man on a mission to introduce
his country's Cuisine to the world
though he hails from Islamabad he hopes
to one day retire in this region one
other interesting thing about the food
here is they didn't add any spices no
sugar because how they like the food
that every ingredient has its own flavor
right here this is the pancake here she
has apricot oil she just DED these with
oil with this oil you can dump it as
much as you want and you shouldn't feel
guilty because it's a very healthy oil
try it
[Music]
out if you like sweet you e honey okay
it's not sweet now it tastes almost more
like a crepe than a pancake which might
have eggs in it the apricot oil I can't
say it has a lot of flavor it's food
Loop it kind of makes it easier to slide
down your throat yeah it's very
impressive very interesting to see in
this side of Pakistan because people if
they know anything at all about Pakistan
is probably more about the big cities
and the hustle and the bustle and the
parts that have some similarities to
India here completely different culture
and different foods it's obviously
reflected here in what we're eating
right now less seasonings super local
ingredients nothing too intense I love
it very
nice the hunza people or the hunza cots
are ethnically known as the Baro people
with a population of
60,000 they have their own distinct
language musical instruments clothing
and
Customs residing in the highlands of the
Himalayas they're known for their
longevity with an unofficial life
expectancy of 100 years are your
grandparents around yeah how old are
your grandparents 100 and they're alive
yeah that's pretty good this is kind of
what today is about one seeing a
different lifestyle a different way of
eating and living here in Pakistan but
also trying to understand what is so
different here that allows people to
live these long healthy lives I'm very
impressed by that I must learn
more ma'am good day how are you I am
fine how are you I'm I'm so excited to
be here meet Miss L Maadi in her cozy
Mountainside kitchen for 17 years she's
been whipping up Regional favorites for
locals and visitors alike what are you
doing right now I'm
making this is the most vegetables I've
seen so far on my trip so you already
made this for us is chpo it looks kind
of like CH local pizza it's a local
pizza yeah yeah wheat dough is kned into
a round shape add the filling made of
chicken and local spices what is inside
chicken coriander mint onion GRE link
local zaan garlic ginger litter salt
cooking Walnut and a pric oil you just
gave away your whole recipe are you
worried about that thank you yeah cover
it with another layer of dough then cook
it in a hot pan with apricot oil when
both sides turn golden brown cut and
serve with goat
[Music]
cheese M oh so good tastes like a whole
wheat wrapper on the outside and then
inside it's just so flavorful it's spicy
you could taste the C there's a ton of
harmonized onion coming through so what
I like about this is that after having a
breakfast which probably didn't have
much taste to it this is like a nice
contrast yeah absolutely I'm going to
give it a little bit of a dip here a
beautiful pairing clean cool refreshing
and sweet to go with something a little
bit more heavy and a lot more spicy this
is delicious thank you how did you learn
to cook in my own grandmother okay how
old is your grandmother 99 year she is
the yeah oh she passed away but when she
was 99 that's remarkable my grand father
is 104 years right now no he passed away
yeah but 104 and the one secret that is
the organic food but plenty of people in
the USA eat organic food it's not
working out for them having organic food
just for like a few years just to
satisfy your own cell is something else
but being raised in this very
environment and you keep on having that
for your entire life is different are
you saying it's too late for me yeah a
bit too late okay it's never too late
the diet here may be a key factor in
hunza longevity organic raw vegetables
fruits and moderate protein consumption
mineral Rich Mountain Water is plentiful
and then there's this the priced apricot
rich in vitamin A and other antioxidants
this food is omnipresent in hunza
cooking used for its fruit seed and oil
sometimes a lot of oil like in our next
dish this is Mor Prett this is mulita
add water to a pot then add dry Cow
Cheese dried mint salt coriander onion
green chilies and small crumbs of
chapati
cook to with apricot
oil it's ready bro bro this looks
stunning this is food for the soul and
also stomach we have a couple other ones
here I think we'll build up to this
first we have this I don't know what
you'd call this soup or stew this one is
called gig Al meaning Brown lentil and
potato a type of Stew that's eaten with
chipati made by stir frying coriander
paste mint and green chilies in a pot
add Masala water Brown lentils salt and
potatoes cook and serve I'm want to put
some lentil some potato on here kind of
a natural gravy that's come from all
that let's try it
[Music]
out M that super yummy as lentil as
potatoes but has a nice texture and
great flavor man this feels like real
home-cooked food none of these like
super intense straight Food flavors and
what really love about it is so spicy in
the right way yeah it's like warming me
up from the inside this one is called
mulita in the middle there's a pool of
oil which uh is bringing me back to the
L hor Vibes there is a reservoir right
here of just butter sorry butter I want
to see if I can taste the oil directly
and see if it has any flavor oh yeah
when you eat it just alone it has a
little flowery Essence to it do we mix
all that together take a spoonful of
mulita dip the spoon in this and then
let's just go for it
oh oh oh this is the most confusing
thing I've ever eaten but I genuinely
like it I don't know where the flavors
are coming from I don't know how they're
combining it's like Dairy but then it's
also spice it's like putting Tabasco in
your yogurt in the morning there's a lot
going on in my mouth right now that's
what I was trying to say that had four
taste phases so there's like a powdered
cheese in there dehydrated Cow Cheese
that has its own unique flavor first
it's like creamy and cheesy like paneer
and then it gets a little bit gy after
that there's some FL s coming from this
oil it does have some spice but it's not
all like CID and coriander it has its
own flavor profile super unique sure Mor
takes the crown this is no joke it's one
of the most beautiful places I've ever
seen in my life I can't believe it every
time I look out there I'm like that's CG
that's not
real why do you think this part of the
world is so unknown to so many
definitely in Pakistan we had our
realities couple of years ago because of
all the Law and Order situation going on
so the kind of media word that the world
was getting was not very positive but
alhamdulillah things have become
absolutely normal and now tourism is
getting back to Pakistan but other than
that to be honest this part of Pakistan
they are super peaceful in fact for your
audience I mean they're lucky to see all
of this but they're unlucky in a way
that the camera cannot capture the
reality what the eyes can see so for
that they have to come and see it for
themselves I believe the Nature has its
own filter when you come to this part of
Pakistan it's so beautiful like I mean
well Ali this has been very romantic my
wife she would really enjoy this but at
least I'm here with you that's nice
stuck with me yeah restaurants like this
slightly alter their traditional recipes
to suit visitors from other parts of
Pakistan who prefer stronger more spicy
flavors I'm realizing now the only way
to truly experience what it means to eat
like a hakot is to go to someone's home
you've come to another home in the same
Village the home has very similar
architecture even if you look up there
that is the Skylight this time we are in
the base we're going to make a chapati
it's a cheese chapati yeah ah I like
cheese she starts with the bottom layer
rolling it out she puts it on there I
love the way the traditional kitchen
work here this is basically a fire
inside of here and then they can adjust
the tops that they put on so this one is
for making chapati but they have other
ones where they can put big pots on
there whatever you need they even have
one that can uh make french fries that's
not true so right now she's put down the
first layer and she's going to add in
some of the filling this paste is made
from cottage cheese coriander green
onion Walnut salt and a little bit of
milk chati number two it goes on and now
we have a little walnut
oil a generous portion of walnut
oil this is nasba and her sister what's
your name on baby nice to meet you my
name is sunny in my language Sunny means
legendary
eater you know I've eaten uh seven
things today okay how many things did
you eat tea and bread I like this bread
this this is a corn wheat this is
essentially cornbread right here oh you
ate it
already oh I just put twoo big in a
piece it's very when you eat this bread
then not
speaking because it makes your mouth so
dry finish this bread then talk that's a
really good idea it's just like any good
cornbread it absorbs all the saliva in
your mouth please
wait 10 minutes
[Music]
done yeah can I tell you something today
I ate eight Foods cuz I had
[Music]
that we have our dinner here this looks
incredible so they've cooked something
that we saw already but it looks
slightly different this is the m right
also with the oil in there but so many
other dishes here we've got a chicken
noodle soup buckwhat pancakes cheese
chipati some dumplings and then a
dessert can we start with these
dumplings The Filling is made of minced
chicken coriander green onions and green
chilies that is wrapped in a wheat flour
dough and
steamed these may look like East Asian
duml but here they're called Mandu in
Korea this exact same thing is called
Mandu there's no way that's a
coincidence of the same food has a
similar sounding name because the area
that we are right now is almost
bordering China and Central Asia so
that's why you find dumplings here but
not in La so different that fascinating
it has a really interesting combination
of meat it's like half meat half
vegetable it tastes a little bit dry not
super juicy but a spicy a little bit
more mild gentle flavors here they have
cheese chipati let's try it
out it's good it's SM cheesy it tastes
almost like cream cheese with some
chives inside what's your favorite food
here this one this is a soup sauté
chopped onions ground ginger and garlic
in olive oil add in minced chicken
ginger more spices and boil when the
noodles join the pot you're minutes away
from completion let's go for
it oh that's delicious super Savory
really soft noodles almost like a f
noodle chicken is really tender and
trust me I love a soup with no bones I
hate when they give you soup and you
have to do some of the work like pull
bones out of your mouth put them on the
table this is very good this is the
buckwheat pancake quite different than
the ones that we had in the breakfast is
this something you eat a lot so she's
saying that this is one contributing
factor to the longevity of the Local H
of people it tastes healthy Buck weed is
highly recommended for various health
problems can it help gas no
okay finally this is a dessert it has a
pool a reservoir right in the middle
full of oil this is walnut oil there are
crushed walnuts all around it but then
this brown Mass what is that this brown
component is basically made from organic
local wheat flour so what they do is
that they age the local wheat for 5 6
days in water and somehow it become
sweet so a lot of work goes into this
for sure so now she's working her way
around the perimeter so you can see it's
really thick she gets plenty of that oil
on there let's try it
[Music]
out the source of the hunza Fountain of
Youth is debated by many mhm this is one
of the best desserts I've ever had it's
so fun to chew through and then really
dense sweet texture is it the diet here
is it the Mountain Water fresh air high
elevation the copious amounts of apricot
consumption perhaps it's stress living
or the fact that traditionally local
folks would walk the mountains and work
the fields for most hours of the day
you've been here your whole life as this
place changed much since you were a
kid the biggest defining change for her
in this entire region is tourism because
back then there used to be very few
tourists but now like tourists are
coming in big numbers so that has
changed the overall landscape of the
area and now kids are more focused
toward studies rather than working in
the fields which her generation used to
do back then so now yeah the people are
adjusting to the new trends in a good
way because when you walk around these
Villages these Alleyways you know you
feel these people are loyal to their
customs and their tradition fascinating
thank you so much for inviting us into
your home for the food and for the
company I really appreciate
it next you're going to see how a
village Cooks up an entire Yak in
Pakistan he's going to take off the lid
and we unveil the most magnificent pot
of yak and rice I have ever seen in my
life but first let's back
up only some animals can survive this
harsh terrain and the extreme weather of
hunza I came from the enter the yak a
domesticated wild ox that thrives in
cold used for its fur milk and meat this
looks incredible what is that a hip when
I need a hip replacement surgery let me
know I will send it to you thank you
here it's consumed on rare and special
occasions an occasion like today
[Music]
joining me today Sher he spent his life
among this mountain range of the hunza
valley right now we're on our way up the
mountain to meet a yak dealer who spent
the night coming down to meet us
halfway
gentlemen good morning right now there
is a yak about 15 ft behind
me what does a yak do before it attacks
you it will make some sound with his
nose
okay it's eating grass we're good for a
little bit I'm very excited I have
traveled to many countries I've tried
many different types of animals this
will be my first time trying Yak meat
just seeing it up close for the first
time in my life right now it's
incredible and it inspires a little bit
of fear cuz at any moment it could come
charging this way and then we're done
for or else I have to jump off the
mountain how much does this Yak weigh
250 yeah that's it Oh I thought it was a
lot more than them
time he
Yaks live at the highest altitude of any
animal compared to an ox the yak has
humped shoulders large horns heavy skin
and long shaggy hair that insulates it
from extreme cold when they are full
with their stomach they sit on the snow
anywhere and when the water get Freez
they eat the snow that's the way of
surviving Yaks are badass they don't
tolerate the cold they're build for it
it's about 50° here but even this
temperature is way too hot for the yak
what temperature do they like minus
tempure just under freezing yeah these
particular harsh conditions make the
difficult job of yak hurting well not
for everyone Karine here well he's been
doing it for over 30 years you've
brought this Yak since 3:00 a.m. how
hard is it to travel with a yak for him
from the top of hor pass it's around
4,100 M from sea level it's a really
tough job sometime it's attacking
[Music]
also Yaks are slaughtered between the
ages of three and six when it's time
they can weigh over 2,000 lb what you
guys are about to see and what's going
to happen today is nothing new for this
community everyone's going to be here
women children kids and all of them are
going to see from beginning to end the
entire process from slaughtering to the
final meal this is a really special
experience cuz you have to travel so far
to this isolated region not only in the
world but it's isolated within Pakistan
any moment that yak is going to pull up
and we're going to see what happens from
there
[Music]
Broad and Powerful as he
is the yak is not Invincible to
experienced hands
[Music]
like many times before the familiar
villagers work in harmony to begin the
butchering
process
skinning removing organs all will be
used all except the blood as we are
still in a Muslim Community in the
Muslim country of
Pakistan why are people eating yak and
not just beef from a cow as we are
living in Mountain we have this
opportunity to keep this kind of
animals and Y meat is better compared to
another beef like Buffalo or cow because
the Ys eat the nature HBS in the
mountains so y meat is more softer and
more delicious with several dishes ahead
each portion each cut of meat is sliced
and diced with a final destination in
mind our dinner of yak meat is more than
half a day and many hours of work
away in the meantime breakfast
an omelette cooked with onions and
tomatoes Kata made from wheat
dough twisted up to give it a signature
flaky texture flatten and toss it on the
flat
top any hearty breakfast must also be
joined by a powerful life-giving
beverage mostly here in mon areas we
have the salty tea we use the salt in
tea um I feel like it's too
much this is the pink himan salt you
just need to
oh really yeah across from Zarin bik and
local teacher a little bit of a dim and
then do I take a little bite no you just
SI that
tea oh that's salty interesting if you
want this here you can put some butter
in it and you can take a piece of this
FY this is a thick bread I like that
your tea is also a meal to try it out M
that's delicious there's some nice
richness from the butter and the bread
is just really soft saturated soaking up
all that salty tea I like it this is our
tradition way of sharing the food o that
was awesome and then I use this to pick
up the egg yeah that's a Bigg T
cry M that delicious little veggie
omelette nice soft weedy bread it's like
a little breakfast
burrito
burritos it's one of the best things out
there so I noticed breakfast would
usually be no meat but if you're eating
meat one would it be dinner and lunch is
it common for the people in the village
to eat Yak yeah they do especially in
Winters we mostly eat the YK
meat because beef has got this property
that it keeps here warmer whole day long
and Winters are really harsh in here so
they dry up the meat and they keep it
for months and they cut the beef from
there and they just cook
it this is our head chef pamant Karim
this plot of land is his and it will
serve as the perfect outdoor kitchen as
cooking stations pop up throughout the
day reinforcements are headed here from
the base of the mountain but for now
we've got work to
[Music]
do today's Yak hundreds of pounds of
meat will be cooked five different ways
first up the boil this is Supra it
requires one back leg simmering for 3
hours along with onion ginger garlic and
salt cooking is underway we have our
whole outside area set up here there's
about 10 or 12 people working together
to make this big Feast happen we have to
have all this done in 2 and 1/2 hours
this is Extreme cooking so take a look
at he's already been boiling this for
almost a couple hours now yeah okay look
at that you can see the limb is starting
to render down it's going to get really
cooked get really soft this is one of
the main things I eat here and they can
also use the juice itself to make rice
so that's something they plan on doing
soon they also have super loud tractors
like that one got to love the guy way
out in the countryside with a CO mask
around his chin safety so that's just
one of our dishes back here we also have
a dish with meat and potatoes this is
Alo ghost a type of meat curry add the
ribs to the
pot then chopped
[Applause]
onion a garlic ginger salt mixture and
curry powder then cook it for an hour
and a half what I love is that when he's
cooking he doesn't have some metal spoon
or a little spatula he has this can I
hold this for one second it's a piece of
rebar this is what you put in concrete
to make it stronger when you pour
concrete and they've had a blacksmith
flattened out the tip right here so we
can use it to cook huge portions of food
how cool is that right now he is going
to put in the potato oh he just puts in
a little bit of first you don't want to
overdo it intimidate it overwhelm it
like me to girls when I was in high
school the fire is doing its job the
meat is stewing the curry Cooks low and
slow and if you're in the right place at
the right time you'll find little morels
that are already ready to munch on right
now we have some barbecue though it is
not the typical H food but it is
Pakistani this is yak Kebab the chef
uses meat from the backbone then
marinate with ginger garlic juice red
chili powder salt lemon juice garlic
powder vinegar and cooking
oil skewer the meat and Grill it over
charcoal it's going to be my first bite
ever of yak let's
[Music]
go
mhm M it's interesting it has a lot of
seasoning on it the Masala it's a bit
spicy and very powerful so it's hard to
taste what the animal tastes like it
feels a little bit beefy it is beef be
that's beef we count it as a beef but it
is softer than the other beef absolutely
it's so tender it's delicious I mean
it's been grilled so there's a little
crunchy bits on the edges but still
inside not dry at all other thing I want
to add in this the high blood pressure
patients cannot eat the beef because it
got high cholesterol but the same
patient can eat reak me there's a lot of
people with high blood pressure that
watch my show okay so it's a revelation
that's great
[Music]
news this is a favorite all over Central
Asia the ways of referring to the dish
and what you put in it depends on where
you are
precisely it's the centerpiece for many
important communal
events
p a rich fragrant rice based dish loaded
with plenty of protein hits the pot with
onion carrots cumin cumin leaves tomato
palow spices chicken powder coconut
flesh almonds raisins and
sugar look at that it is magnificent
beautiful bubbling meat you can just
smell the spices coming through in the
steam I've already had a little bit of a
taste but I think here is where I'm
going to really experience big succulent
soft cuts of yak meat this is my dream
scenario remember the Supra from earlier
they add that potent Supra stock to this
palow
pot those deep fatty Yak flavors will
now soak into the BOS body rice see this
isn't the kind of food show where we
pretend everything's going to go great
and then we smile and eat at the end and
we say oh what a happy ending no we were
in laor we had a chef he tried to cook a
whole goat underground we waited 3 hours
pulled it
out that looks like half an inch roughly
is probably cooked and then under that
pretty raw something similar with us
here we no nothing similar please no I
mean the food we take 3 hours oh this
will be done properly and you will enjoy
it all right right here we have another
appetizer something we can try out
before the main Feast that's going to be
taking place in a couple of hours with
all the different animals I've eaten
through my different travels I've
noticed they all have a little bit
different feeling with their organs for
example I had camel recently in Egypt
and that was a trip like the heart
tasted like liver the liver tasted weird
and snappy and spongy wow delicious so
I'm going to see here if the yak liver
and the yak heart have their own unique
properties flavors and textures chop
them up into bite-sized pieces marinate
with salt ginger garlic juice lemon
juice and Tika a type of barbecue spice
then simply deep fry all right I want to
share something with my man right here
and that's liver yes
cheers I like this prep cuz it's fried
oh man that's one of the best liver I've
ever had this knocks the socks off of
Regular beef liver from a freaking cow
often times beef liver sometimes it gets
overcooked it dries out your mouth when
you eat it this is great crunchy on the
outside when you look at the inside it
looks like it would dry but it's not
it's not even Livery if we're talking
organs my favorite organ it's not the
liver it's not the lungs it's not the
penis why was that third on my list it's
the heart I like it cuz it's so dense
I'm going to rip this in half I'm
curious what this looks like oh yeah see
just super dense beautiful
meat wow super moist soft tender super
juicy seriously best animal heart I've
ever had in my life
ladies and gentlemen it is just a couple
hours before Sundown people are arriving
villagers are hungry and excited we are
going to unveil the palow right now he
takes off these two cement blocks here
Embers still really flipping hot on top
to help cook it from the top and the
bottom he's going to take off the lid
and we unveil the most magnificent pot
of yak and rice I have ever seen in my
life would you take a look at
this the Aromas is really good oh oh my
gosh this is that beautiful basmati rice
into long grains vegetables tons of meat
all mixed together this looks incredible
I can't believe what they've come up
with here well done these are our two
main chefs for today they have been
busting their beehinds to get this all
done in time and we've done it so from
here they're going to serve it up put it
on some platters and some plates bring
it over to a carpet where everyone can
sit together we're going to eat and have
a good time let's do
this a feast is nothing without its
community
Community some finish off cooking some
start assembling plates and delivering
food while others sit
patiently waiting for the socially
acceptable moment to dig
[Music]
in across from me local Pakistani and my
good friend Ali gentlemen we've done it
yes there may have been small
disappointments obstacles to be overcome
during during this trip I can't remember
any of them maybe the goat I guess just
a Stubborn Goat it was a Stubborn Goat
but today my friend I see a lot of yak
meat all the way cooked through five
different courses today this looks
incredible this is a pout over here we
have the Alo go plenty of yak meat super
soft and tender with potatoes and then
this is where I need clarification
because this is a Supra this soup is not
looking that soupy to me it is very
super you can see actually we mostly eat
as a dry please grab a chunk of meat for
me it's a very special moment this is my
first piece of yak ever oh that's so
awesome dude cheers cheers to
Yak M I believe this is even softer than
beef yeah it's so soft you don't have to
cut it you can peel it off the bone
which is incredible beyond that you can
feel some of the fat has boiled out cuz
it went into the water and of course you
use that water to make this rice but it
still has plenty of
flavor if there's one dish which can be
called the national food of Pakistan
it's all ghost oh is that right like
this is this is one food which you get
in every Province almost in every city
and people love it the meat changes from
one place to another so for example to
Punjab they're probably using goat meat
or chicken for that matter well here Yak
is the local animal so we use Yak meat
what is so loved about Alo ghost once
you try it for yourself you'll see that
the combination is so perfect M mhm oh
that's so good it's been brazing for
hours so the meat is so soft the
intermuscular fat that just been
rendering down all the connective
tissues and tendons has been kind of
melting down
the real way to eat Alo ghost is with
Roti kick and potato and meat some
curries then have
it epic
bite make sure to take the bones out
okay good
idea to me it doesn't even taste like a
curry I mean it doesn't have that big
multitude of Curry type spices it's just
more like a delicious Yak gravy or
reduction potatoes are cooked perfectly
little form a little bit soft but the
yak is incredible it is like the best
version of beef in my opinion V you beef
well not quite have you had walk you
no
no finally we have this food right here
this is the pal here's what I was
wondering in usbekistan they eat
something called P but it must have a
similar root cuz there's rice there's
meat they're cooked together yes so back
in the days when the Traders through S
crw used to come to these areas they
just not used to trade goods also
cultures and customs and words and
languages and food so I'm sure paao came
to this region from Central Asia and
then you obviously improvised it look at
this there's still big pieces of meat in
there too mhm and then some of that
Rice oh that's so satisfying I taste the
cumin is super Savory red chili powder
the rice is so perfectly seasoned is
separated from each other grain the
mouth feel is so good and I'm sure the
soup from this Supra is adding tons of
flavor to this poow I think that's what
it is it really has a depth of flavor
that's hard to put into words that yak
stock the yak attack coming from over
here is transferred into the rice and
it's just absorbed wonderfully woo that
is good what do you think yes
yes I knew nothing about Pakistan when I
started this trip I know other people
had travel here I saw some videos here
and there what people were doing I knew
it used to be part of Hindustan and so
there was some connections between
Pakistan and India and that was my only
references we started in lore and I got
those same Vibes in the
past very bustling busy City tuck tuck
horses coming through the street
sometimes street food noise just very
vibrant but then here this place is like
no place I've ever been before it's
interesting cuz in some ways it feels
completely separated from what I know as
Pakistan but at the same time it's just
another part or another facet of this
country yeah for sure like Gil bstan
hunza this region is called Jewel of
Pakistan I believe it's the best that we
have in terms of the Beauty look at the
landscape and the people they're so
simple hospitable so this place indeed
has best of everything I love in as long
as I've been doing the show 500 episodes
thousands of different foods I still can
be surprised there's still different
pockets and corners of the world that
I've yet to see that are still blowing
my mind and this is absolutely one of
them gentlemen thank you so much this
has been quite an experience we have
plenty more food to dig into cheers to
[Music]
Pakistan guys oh my gosh I can't believe
it we've done it five videos here in
Pakistan it is the end of this trip but
not the end of you know all the trips my
point is we're going to come back thank
you so much for inviting us and for
being such a wonderful ambassador to
this country thank you so much for
coming I to you on behalf of every
Pakistani I'm sure your content will
show the world the true and real face of
Pakistan thank you so much are we
holding hand to this point when does it
become you know once it stop being a
hand shank and start I'm just getting
sentimental that you're leaving I no
it's emotional oh are you crying behind
your prescription sunglasses I'm hiding
my tears okay good well that's it for
this one guys thank you so much for
watching I will see you next time a
peace the final piece from Pakistan all
right let's go let's go get some but but
but and Buton I'm yuck I like how you
say yeah it's like yoke how do you say
yuck now you changed it